we've been given
a string of colors referenced by the
variable colors
and this problem asks us to print true
if colors includes the color yellow and
print false if it doesn't
and print true if colors includes the
color purple and print false if it
doesn't
so let's begin with the color yellow
we can use the string include method
include returns a boolean either true
or false depending on whether the
calling string
includes the string passed in as an
argument
so in this case we want to pass in the
string
yellow as an argument
and we expect that our invocation of
include will return true
because we can see that the string
colors
does indeed have the word yellow in it
let's output the return value of this
method invocation
and you can see that it does return true
one important thing to note is that
include is
case sensitive
if i were to capitalize the word yellow
that i've passed in as an argument
include will return false
and we can see that by running our code
again
recall that in ruby
comparison of strings is case sensitive
when i compare two words with the same
letters of different cases
ruby will return false
in order for an equality comparison of
two strings to return
true they must contain letters of the
same case
so keep that in mind when using methods
such as
include to check for certain values in a
string
now the second step of this problem is
to check whether the string
colors includes purple
and in this case we expect that our
invocation of include will return false
and it does
another thing to keep in mind when using
the include method
is that it's checking whether the
calling string
includes the pattern passed in as an
argument
not necessarily whether the argument is
its own word in the string
so for example on line 5 i've passed in
ink as the argument to include while we
don't see the word ink in our colors
string
we do have the word pink which includes
that sequence of characters
so let's run our code and see what our
invocation of include returns in this
case
it returns true
so the include method can be very useful
but
be aware of its limitations
you